《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》 前情提要
BALTAR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我  莎伦・阿格森  作为殖民舰队军官
I, Sharon Agathon, will carry out the lawful orders of my superiors
将执行上级的命令
as an officer in the Colonial Fleet.
祝贺你  少尉
Congratulations, Lieutenant.
我们在谈论的是那些把自己炸成碎片的人们
I'm talking about people blowing themselves up.
我已经在这里找到了工作
I've got one job here,
女士 也是唯一的工作 就是瓦解赛昂人
lady, and one job only, to disrupt the Cylons,
让他们对任他们摆布的蝼蚁感到恐惧
make them worry about this anthill they've stirred up down here,
他们会转移注意力 当老头子回来时 会躲过他们的视线
so they're distracted and out of position when the old man shows up in orbit.
你们也知道了任务
You know the mission.
你们也该知道这次任务只能以一种方式结束
You should also know there's only one way this mission ends,
那就是从新卡布里卡成功营救我们的人民
and that's with the successful rescue of our people off of New Caprica.
从整个设施中撤离
Evacuate the entire facility.
你也应该和我们一起走 盖尤斯 我们也给你留了个位置
You should go as well, Gaius. There's a place for you, too.
上尉 嘿 这是谁?
Captain? Hi. Who's this?
这是…
This is...
凯西
Kacey.
噢  我的乖女儿
Oh, my little girl!
当赛昂人带走她的时候  我以为…
When the Cylons took her, I thought...
但你救了她
But you saved her.
神保佑你
Gods bless you.
嗨
Hey.
很多好人都付出了代价 为他们所做的
A lot of good people had to pay the price for what they did,
他们在新卡布里卡所做的决定 就像我的老婆
the choices they made on New Caprica, like my wife.
没错  艾伦通了敌
That's right. Ellen collaborated.
把地下抵抗组织的信息透露给了赛昂人 她付出了生命的代价
She gave the Cylons information on the resistance and she died for it.
我简直不能想象还有人在质疑我的价值
I can't believe there's still a question of my value.
那肯定会是个问题的
There will always be a question.
你是一个人类
You're human.
很高兴见到你
BALTAR: Good to see you.
我很喜欢这些风景来作为我们会面的背景 你喜欢吗?
I far prefer these picturesque settings for our little interludes, don't you?
我还以为你把我抛弃给了你的赛昂人伙伴呢
I thought you'd abandoned me to your Cylon comrades.
我该那么做吗?
NO. 6: Would I do that?
你一直都比你的实体副本…
BALTAR: You've always been more unpredictable
更难以预知
than your flesh-and-blood counterparts.
一个像你一样恋爱经历丰富的男人
NO. 6: A man that loves women as much as you
早就应该明白这些了吧
should have learned that a long time ago.
我学得比较迟钝
I'm a slow learner.
那就把这段当作
Then take this period as a time to learn
了解什么是赛昂人的经历吧
all you can about the Cylons.
你以后会用得到的
You'll need it in the days ahead.
有什么特殊的地方吗?
Something special on the horizon?
赛昂人的心理活动是基于心理投射
Cylon psychology is based on projection.
心理投射?
Projection?
那是他们观察周围环境的方法
It's how they choose to see the world around them.
唯一的不同是你选择了看到我
The only difference is you choose to see me.
那你是谁呢?
What are you?
是真实的吗?
Really?
你是我与卡布里卡上所认识的那个女人的连线(结果)
You're either connected to the woman I knew on Caprica,
还是我下意识在努力自我表现的一部分?
or you're a damaged part of my subconscious
你到底是哪一个?
struggling for self-expression, so which one is it?
我是上帝派来帮你的天使
I'm an angel of God sent here to help you,
正如我过去一直所做的
just as I always have been.
我们同是一个巨大生态系统中的一部分
We're all part of one big ecosystem.
是的  我能感觉到它在     呼吸
Yes, I can feel it. Breathing.
要习惯
Get used to it.
呃  他怎么说?
So, what'd he say?
我还没问呢
I haven't asked him yet.
问我什么?
Ask me about what?
地球
Earth.
呃…
Well...
地球 第13个殖民星球
Earth, it's the Thirteenth Colony.
知道怎么找到它吗?
Do you know how to find it?
不太清楚  不
Not really, no.
那  这就太不幸了
D'ANNA: Well, that's unfortunate.
如果你知道去地球的方法 还有一线希望
There was a hope, my hope, that if you knew the way to Earth,
那能确保让你活得更久一些
it would justify keeping you alive a little longer.
走吧  6号
Come on, Six.
等等 等下  等下!
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
我说我不知道地球的具体位置
Now, when I say that I do not know exactly where Earth is,
并不意味我不知道
that is not to say that I do not know
大量关于地球大概位置的信息
a very great deal about its probable location
坦白地说  我花了多少小时 多少天
Honestly, I spent hours, days,
多少周  多少月嗯是多少个月
weeks, months and months on a map
在阿达玛和罗丝琳从科波发现的地图上
that Adama and Roslin found on Kobol.
并且我将它们与天体测量联系起来
And I correlated that with our astrometric observations.
我怀疑这里是否有人能做这些
I doubt anyone here can make the same claim.
我们会回来找你的
We'll get back to you.
你们要知道地球干吗?
What do you care about finding Earth?
因为我们在找它
Because we're looking for it.
你们?
You are?
是的  我们决定把地球当作 我们的新家
Yes. We've decided that Earth is going to be our new home.
现授权可以进行一对一的飞船训练 你们准备好以后就开始
HELO: Ship-to-ship training exercise is authorized. You may commence when ready.
这里是阿波罗 红队已准备好
This is Apollo. Red Team set.
蓝队已准备好
KAT: Blue Team set.
红队 阿波罗
Red Team, Apollo.
当我们穿过这颗卫星 我们就会出现在他们的雷达上
As soon as we clear the moon we're gonna be on their dradis,
所以说  大家都打起精神
so keep your eyes up.
他们会全力进攻我们的
They're gonna hit us with everything they've got.
保持编队 星芭  Narcho 你做我的僚机
APOLLO: Stay in formation, Starbuck. Narcho, you're my wingman.
蓝队  凯特  让我们教一下那些懒家伙该怎么开飞机
Blue Team, Kat. Let's show these lazy fraks how it's done.
红队 星芭 我发现了热狗
Red Team, Starbuck. I've got Hotdog.
我被击中!
I'm hit!
红队 阿波罗 我在追踪凯特
Red Team, Apollo. I'm going after Kat.
凯特…
Kat...
你就这种水平吗  阿波罗  再来啊
You're gonna have to do better than that, Apollo! Come on!
我来对付凯特
STARBUCK: I'll take care of Kat.
星芭 你要保持队形!  Narcho在追击凯特
APOLLO: Starbuck, you stay in formation. Narcho has Kat.
归航
Inbound.
星芭 你太近了
APOLLO: Starbuck, you're too close!
哦！
STARBUCK: Oh!
靠!
Frak!
压缩机挂了 看起来像被东西刮了
A compressor blew. It looks like it threw a blade.
供油线路被碰坏了 凯莉  查下油箱      天啊
It severed the fuel line. Cally, check the tank! Gods this is ugly.
油箱都空了 这里都没有任何燃料
The tank's bone-dry. There's not even fumes in here.
上尉  你是怎么降落的?
TYROL: Captain, how'd you land this thing?
将它对准甲板  在我到那的时候就停下来
Pointed it toward the deck and stopped when I got here.
都漏光了  她说   把没有一点燃料的"小鸟"飞回来了
"Bone-dry," she says. Landed the bird without a drop of fuel.
如果你想死 你可以去减压舱
If you want to die, I will open up an airlock for you.
但你不能连累我的其中一架蝮蛇机和你一起完蛋!
But you are not taking one of my Vipers with you.
"小鸟"在甲板上  我也在甲板上
The "bird's" on the deck. I'm on the deck.
我不知道你还在吠什么
I don't know what you're bitching about.
我不会原谅你的所作所为  星芭
I don't give a frak what you do, Starbuck.
你被停飞了
You're done flying.
不能想象你会那样对我
ELLEN: I can't believe you did that to me.
什么?
What?
不要这样看着我
Don't look at me like that.
噢  我的天
Oh, my Gods.
艾伦?
Ellen?
Ellen!
请让让  请让路  让让
Excuse me. Move ahead, make a hole.
请让让
Excuse me.
艾伦
Ellen?
我不是跟你说过了吗 我跟你说了上千次了吧
WOMAN: If I've told you once, I've told you 1,000 times...
艾伦  我在这儿
Ellen! I'm right here!
你是谁?放开我
What is this? Let go of me.
卡拉  卡拉!
KACEY: Kara! Kara!
凯西?
Kacey?
卡拉  卡拉
Kara! Kara!
瑟瑞丝上尉?  对不起  你不认识我了吗?
Captain Thrace? I'm sorry, don't you remember me?
我是Julia Prynne  凯西的妈妈
I'm Julia Prynne. I'm Kacey's mom.
当然  当然  我记得
Yeah. Yeah, I remember.
抱抱我
Give me a hug.
我们现在一直都住在
We've been staying over in the,
大家都把那里称作滑油营
well, everyone's calling it "Camp Oil Slick. "
那是飞行甲板的一部分 他们在那搭了帐篷  你听说了吧 难民
Part of the hangar deck and they've put up cots for, you know, refugees.
是的  我听说了
Yeah. Yeah, I heard.
那好  凯西已经喊了好多天要见你
Well, Kacey's been asking to see you for days.
我让人给你捎了信息 我以为你会过来看看
And I sent messages and I thought maybe, you know, you'd come to visit.
我知道你是个好人
You seem like a really nice person,
所以我也跟你说实话
so I'm gonna be honest with you.
我所需要的只是一个两岁大的玩伴
The last thing I need is a two-year-old friend.
同时凯西也确信在她以后生活中不再需要我
And Kacey sure as hell does not need me in her life,
所以请你帮帮忙不要把她再带过来  好吗?
so do us both a favor and do not bring her around here again, okay?
让你妈抱你吧  凯西
Go to your mom, Kace.
好的
Sure.
不好意思  别让我们再打扰了你了
Sorry. Don't let us keep you up.
对不起  宝贝  我们得走了
Sorry, honey, we've got to go.
减下去了
There it goes.
就是
That's that.
看到了吧?
See?
看到了吧  我说过你能行的
See? I told you, you could do it.
你做得非常好
You did great.
我以后不会再胖起来了
Remind me never to let that happen again.
你瘦下来了
You got it, "Slim. "
再也不了
Ever.
我正在重新整理总统波…
I've been trying to reassemble President...
是波塔尔博士所研究的
Doctor Baltar's work on piecing together
关于去地球的路径的资料
the Thirteenth Tribe's path to Earth.
我很好奇  盖塔先生 你为什么会相信
I'm curious. Mr. Gaeta, what is it that you trust
波塔尔博士的研究成果呢?
about Doctor Baltar's research?
你怎么知道这不是他的又一个骗局呢?
How do you know it's not another one of his lies?
如果还有什么波塔尔的事是我所了解的
If there was one thing I learned about Baltar,
那就是他用于自保的极强的技能
it was his extraordinary capacity for self-preservation.
我认为他很想找到地球 因为他想去那里
I think he wanted to find Earth because he wanted to get there.
他的研究进程怎样了?
How far did he get with his research?
呃  如你所见  我在处理他的这些便笺
Well, as you can see, I'm still hacking through his notes,
但看起来他像是在试图
but it appears that he was trying
与我们的天体测量数据联系起来
to correlate our own astrometric readings
用的是我们在科波所发现的星座地图
with the map of constellations we found back on Kobol.
并且使用他所选取的在皮提亚圣卷轴上一些特殊的段落
Now apply his findings to certain select passages within the scroll of Pythia.
为什么是皮提亚圣卷轴?
Why the scroll of Pythia?
皮提亚被认为记载了
Pythia is supposed to have chronicled the original journey
去第13部落的的原始旅程  就是去地球
of the Thirteenth Tribe on its way to Earth.
我想请大家注意这一段
If I can draw your attention to this passage,
"天空中的船队"
"And the caravan of the heavens was watched over by a great lion,
"有着闪耀眼神的狮子"
"with a mighty blinking eye... "
"用它那红色与蓝色的眼神  注视着"
"Red and blue. "
非常对
GAETA: Exactly.
什么对?
Exactly what?
我们在寻找一个狮头?
We're looking for a lion's head?
用闪耀的眼神
With a mighty blinking eye.
闪耀
Blinking.
嗯  那些古圣卷轴  用暗语写的
Well, these scrolls, they speak in metaphors.
开始  我以为博士的思路搞错了  长官
Initially, I thought the doctor might be off his meds as well, sir,
但当我发现了这张纸
but then I found this note, here,
他在上面写了"闪耀的脉冲双星"
where he had written, "Blinking equals pulsar. "
那是一颗星  对吗?
That means a star, right?
唔  双星  事实上  它们在围绕一个死星旋转
Plural, actually. They're the rotating cores of dead stars.
它释放出来的电磁波
They emit a blast of radio waves.
从远处看  看起来像
From a distance, they appear to...
闪耀着的    没错
Blink. Right.
博士发现的就是这两颗互绕星
GAETA: The doctor found two in very close mutual orbit in this sector.
根据这个成果 通过光谱仪分析后 一颗显示的是红色
The spectrographic readings that I found show one will appear to be red
另一颗显示的是蓝色
and one will appear to be blue.
现在 这颗脉冲星就是在这片星云里
Now, these pulsars appear to be in this nebula.
我们还从未直接观察过这片区域
We have never had a direct look at this area,
但是  有这种可能  如果有人在那个地方看
but it is possible with a couple of eyeballs out there,
他们就能看到星云和
they might look at the nebula and see...
一只巨大狮子的头
A giant lion's head?
很好  看起来这是我们最好的消息了
Well, it looks like this is the best thing we've got going,
呃  如果你不反对  上将  我建议我们去猎狮
so, unless you object, Admiral, I suggest we go lion hunting.
你给我们的导航图好像是有用的
CAPRICA SIX: Navigational markers you gave us may prove useful.
我们派了一艘基地之星去那颗脉冲星
We've sent a Baseship out to investigate the pulsars
去看看你的狮子头
and look for this "lion's head" of yours.
听着  这一切对我并不容易
Look, this isn't easy for me.
我认为你还没有完完全全地感激我 你不知道这一切有多困难
I don't think you fully appreciate just how difficult this is!
我非常矛盾  感觉很痛苦 就是为了帮你找到地球
I have very conflicted, very ambiguous feelings about helping you find Earth.
你表现得真好笑  你那些痛苦的选择  那些内心矛盾
Funny how all that ambivalence and conflict seemed to vanish
当你以为自己的小命快没了的时候
once you thought your life hung in the balance.
你应该知道别人有很多的怀疑
You should know there's still a lot of skepticism
关于我们是否该全信你
about whether you're being entirely truthful.
呃
Uh.
我很抱歉
Very sorry.
我们不是故意闯进来的
We didn't mean to intrude.
拜托  盖尤斯
Come on, Gaius.
我们在绕圈子吗?
BALTAR: Are we going around in circles?
我知道你看起来这些感觉都一样 不是吗?
CAPRICA SIX: Sure it all looks the same to you, doesn't it?
人类在这里是找不到路的 尤其是没有心理投射
It'd be hard for any human to navigate around here, especially without projecting.
是  你曾经对我说过的
Yes. You've used that word before.
我还不敢肯定你说的是什么
I'm not quite sure what you're talking about.
它能帮你干什么  确切地说?
It helps you to what, exactly?
你是否曾做过白日梦
Have you ever daydreamed?
并想象你正身处某处?
You know, imagined that you were somewhere else?
我确实有过这样的经历
I do have an active imagination.
好  我们不需要想象  我们投影背景
Well, we don't have to imagine. We project.
我们可以选择希望见到的背景 在任何时候 以任何形式
We choose to see our environment in any form we wish, whenever we wish.
比方说  现在你看到我们正在一个走廊里走动
For instance, right now, you see us as standing in a hallway,
但我看它是一座森林
but I see it as a forest.
充满了树木  鸟类和阳光
Filled with trees, birds, sunlight.
就像我们过去在卡布里卡上散步
Like walks you and I used to take on Caprica.
是我的审美让我愉快
The aesthetic is what gives me pleasure,
不是什么特殊的记忆
not the specific memories.
为了替换周围的空墙
Instead of staring at blank walls,
我选择如同神造般的景象作我周围的背景
I choose to surround myself with a vision of God's creation.
现在我理解投影的意思了
BALTAR: Right. I think I understand projection,
但那是否同步的?
but, it's a bit of a coincidence, isn't it?
我可以看到自己创造的生动的画面
That I could see such... a vivid reality that I've created
赛昂人投影的经历看起来与我的很相似？
and the Cylon projection experience seems to be so similar?
是不是同步的?
Is it a coincidence?
你说什么?
Well, what are you saying?
这有联系吗?
There's a connection?
什么  因为我和你在一起的经历
What, because of my experiences with you...
我是赛昂人?
Am I a Cylon?
你说什么?
What was that?
噢  没什么只是声音大了点
Oh, nothing. Just... Just talking out loud.
愚蠢的我
Silly me.
那你还想做我的副驾驶吗?
ATHENA: So, are you sure you want to go in second seat again?
我的意思是 我听说你现在是非常好的飞行员
I mean, I hear you're a pretty fair pilot now.
嗯  驾驶员太多了  战机却不够
Yeah, well, too many pilots, not enough birds.
现在  任何能让我飞行的机会
Anything to keep me flying at this point.
你会需要我的  我跟你  布玛尔
You want me, I'm yours, Boomer.
哦  不  布玛尔是...  她不是我
No, Boomer was... She was someone else.
大家听好了 我们要给阿格森少尉起个外号
Listen up! We need a call sign for Lieutenant Agathon!
郭文!    泰坦尼亚
Chromedome! MAN 2:Titania!
猛禽    发条
WOMAN 1: Raptor Adaptor. WOMAN 2: Windup Toy.
罐头    害虫杀手
Tin Can! Vermin Chaser!
雏鸟
MAN 3: Micro Chick.
叫雅典娜怎样?
HOTDOG: How about "Athena"?
信息女神
MAN 4: "Digital Dame. "
等  等  等  等  那是什么呢?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. What was that?
你知道的  那是掌管智慧和战争的女神
You know, the goddess of wisdom and war,
经常陪伴在胜利女神旁边的
usually accompanied by the goddess of victory.
就是它了    很贴切
MAN 5: It works out. MAN 6: She likes it.
那就是雅典娜
Athena it is.
就它了    对 没错
MAN 7: So be it. MAN 8: Okay, deal.
好 你获得这个称号了  还要些什么?
MAN 10: All right, you got that. You want some more?
嘿  上校!  上校  过来坐坐
KAT: Hey, Colonel! Colonel, come have a seat. Over here.
还没玩够吗?
Enough of that to go around?
不会的   哦 是啊
Always. Oh, yeah.
聚魂箱 "杀人"的游戏  不是你的风格嘛
"Deadman's Chest," cutthroat game. Not usually your style.
现在是了 并且我还要赢呢
It is now. And I'm in it to win.
你不喜欢  那就找其他游戏吧
If you don't like it, find another game.
噢  有一些实话要说呢
Now there's some straight talk.
你们没有看到外面排的队吗?
You see the line up outside the head?
15个平民在排队  捏着鼻子
15 civilians standing in line, picking their noses,
等着洗澡
waiting to take a shower.
那帮该死的家伙以为是他们在操作飞船呢
Frakking civilians think they run the ship now.
相比过去  飞船现在像个坟墓
Beats who we had before. Ship was like a tomb.
你想知道孤独是什么感觉吗?
You want to know what "alone" feels like,
那就去赛昂人监狱里待上几周吧
try spending a few weeks in a Cylon holding cell.
是啊  那都是狗屎
Yeah. It was a bitch on both sides.
可拯救你们这些可怜的家伙也不是件容易的事情
It wasn't exactly easy coming up with a plan to save your sorry butts.
你这家伙还不满足  嗯?
Yeah, you guys had it rough, huh?
热水澡  一日三餐
Hot showers, three squares a day.
直到你们跳进轨道 蝮蛇机里的勇士们甚至没开一枪
Viper jocks didn't even take a shot until you jumped into orbit.
我们都有牺牲
Hey. We all made sacrifices.
是那样吗?
That so?
是  那是真的
Yes, that's right.
在你给你的赛昂女朋友佩带飞行章的时候
While you were pinning wings on your Cylon girlfriend,
我们的人正在把自制炸弹绑在胸前
our people were strapping homemade bombs to their chests,
尽可能地将赛昂人轰出去
doing whatever they could to take the bastards out.
所以请原谅我不认同你所说的牺牲
So forgive me if I don't get all misty over your sacrifices.
你看起来心不在焉  盖尤斯
CAPRICA SIX: You seem distracted, Gaius.
我没事
I'm fine.
你可以休息下了  至少现在
You can rest easy, at least for now.
地球位置的资料 还有你勇敢地把那个婴儿救了出来
Data on Earth's location and your valiant rescue of the baby
已经给了其他人一个很深的印象
has gone a long way toward impressing the others.
我一直在想某天能与你生个孩子
I used to think you and I would have a baby one day.
只有12个人形赛昂
There are only 12 Cylon models.
但在新卡布里卡我只看到了七个
But in the entire occupation on New Caprica I only saw seven.
这里也一样  同样的7个赛昂人
Now, here again, the same seven.
另外五个呢?
Who are the Final Five?
我不能说那个
I can't talk about that.
是不能还是不想?     我不能
Can't or won't? I can't.
这很复杂  但我们从不谈论他们
It's complicated. But we don't talk about them, ever.
但你应该认识他们中的一个  不是吗?
But you'd know one of them, wouldn't you,
当你看到这五个赛昂人中的一个
if you saw them, one of the Final Five
假如他们从你身旁走过的时候
if they were to walk past here, right?
6号  我们遇到麻烦了
Six, we have a problem.
那艘基地之星 就是我们派过去调查狮子星云中脉冲星的那艘
A Baseship, the one we sent to investigate the pulsars in the Lion nebula,
我们失去了联络
we've lost contact.
麻烦就在于我们几乎不知道失踪的这艘基地之星的所有状态
The trouble is, we know almost nothing about the missing Baseship's status.
我们收到一个混乱的求救信号 然后就没有消息了
We received a garbled distress call, then silence.
不过  他们的混合体向我们发送了一组被混乱了的数据
Not surprisingly, their Hybrid sent us a confusing set of data.
我们的混合体正在研究它
Our Hybrid is analyzing it.
他所说的混合体是什么?
What are these Hybrids he's talking about?
安静  盖尤斯
Be quiet, Gaius.
我们的混合体正在解译
NO. EIGHT: Our Hybrid's deciphered part of the data set
由我们侦查机捕获的数据
that we received from our scout ship.
这不该发生在我们身上 这不可能
DORAL: This can't happen to us. It's impossible.
不是不可能
SIMON: It is not only possible,
这可能是不可避免的  当我们进化成人形
it may have been inevitable once we took human form.
我们不是人类 我们不像他们
DORAL: We're not human. We're not like him.
上帝选了这个时刻  这个地点来考验我们
LEOBEN: God has chosen this time, this place to test us.
是否能度过这次考验还要靠我们自己
Whether we fail or pass the test is up to us.
怎么样了?
What is going on?
失踪的基地之星可能感染了某种病毒
The missing Baseship, it's been infected with some kind of disease.
病毒?
Disease?
是的  正在杀死他们  所有人
Yes. It's killing them. All of them.
如果一个感染的赛昂人死亡
If an infected Cylon dies and carries
把病毒带着一起返回了复活船
this disease with them into a Resurrection ship,
那可能会快速蔓延 有可能威胁到我们整个族群
it could rapidly spread, potentially infecting our entire race.
好的  我们要确保复活船在安全距离外
All right. We make sure that the Resurrection ship is out of range,
然后我们跳跃到那里
then we jump to their location,
派出一队赛昂武士
send in a group of Centurions to...
不  数据显示在混合体被感染的时候
No. The data set indicates that as soon as their Hybrid was infected,
赛昂武士就开始关闭
their Centurions started shutting down.
我们不能确认我们的是否会被感染
We don't know how ours are gonna be affected.
我想我们的突袭机和基地之星也会被感染的
I assume our Raiders and Baseships are also susceptible.
当然了 我们都是由同一基因池所创造的
Of course. We are all created from the same genetic pool.
没有一个赛昂人能不被感染地登上那艘船
Then no Cylon can board that ship without risking infection.
去说你能登上那艘感染的基地之星
Say you'll go aboard the infected Baseship
并调查发生了什么
and investigate what happened.
是你把他们派去那片星云的 记得吗?
You sent them to that nebula, remember?
你疯了啊?
Are you mad?
你要证明给他们看 你在这种紧急情况下是派得上用场的
You have to prove to them you can be counted on in an emergency.
告诉他们你的存在是有价值的
Show them you're worth keeping alive.
那如果我也感染了病毒呢?
And what if I catch the disease?
一个人感染赛昂武士与突袭机的病
What are the chances that a human could catch something
这机会有多大呢?
that infects a Centurion or a Raider?
并且  如果你是一个人类  或者说  你是个真正的赛昂人
That is, if you're human. And if you're really a Cylon,
是你从未见过的五个中的一个
one of the Final Five you haven't seen yet,
你会让一切都被毁掉并步入灭亡吗?
then wouldn't you just rather get it over with and die?
我去
I'll go.
什么?
What?
是的  我去
Yes, I'll go.
听着  我是一个训练有素的科学家  我可以去基地之星
Look, I am a trained scientist. I can go to the Baseship.
我可以对赛昂人进行观察 检查他们的身体状况
I can make observations about the Cylons, their physical condition,
带回关于那些让你们都在恐惧的病毒的信息
bring back information about this disease which now threatens all of you.
我们已知这种病毒能杀死人形赛昂
We've learned the disease that's killing the human Cylons
也能感染我们的突袭机
could infect one of our Raiders as well.
那就不要派突袭机
Then don't send a Raider.
战争中你们肯定有遗留下某些殖民地的飞船
Surely, the war's furbished you with some Colonial vessels?
他是对的 我们可以设定一驾猛禽机为自动导航飞到那儿
He's right. We could program one of our Raptors to approach on autopilot.
好的  那就准备跳跃
All right, then, prepare to jump the ship.
要确保复活船留在后面  保持安全距离
Make sure the Resurrection ship knows to stay behind, out of range.
多么无私的行动
A truly selfless act.
倒进我这里吧
Hey, I could use a refill here.
你该知道
Here's to knowing
很多人一直在支持你
that somebody will always have your back!
这个观点没错  但在我脑子里
The sentiment's good, but in my book,
信任是价格高昂的日用品
trust is an overrated commodity.
嗯  为它干一杯
That one I'll drink to.
靠  你们这群家伙
Frak you guys.
你有什么问题  凯特瑞恩?
What is your problem, Katraine?
我的问题是你  上尉
My problem is you, Captain.
这都是反对他们的废话
All this "us against them" crap.
事实很残酷  对吧?  再给我一杯
STARBUCK: Truth hurts, doesn't it? Give me another one.
你知道什么  星芭?  不管你在那下面发生了什么
You know what, Starbuck? Whatever happened to you down there,
为何你不把账记在赛昂人头上
why don't you take it out on the Cylons?
因为我们也是使出吃奶的劲去救大家
'Cause we busted our ass to get you off that rock!
你知道那意味着什么吗?
Oh, do you think that means anything?
所有在新卡布里卡上的人员都是忠诚的 无论在哪一个方面
Every colonist that landed on New Caprica was loyal to a point.
我很惊讶地看到一些人
It was amazing watching those people
自以为知道如何反抗赛昂人
that you thought you knew go over to the Cylons.
至少我们知道该怎么做  对吧?
At least, in the end, we knew where we stood, huh?
真如你所说吗?
Is that so?
那为何你在完成飞行任务后
Then how come you are off flight duty
赛昂人的爱人还在占着我的职位?
and some "Cylon-lover" is holding down my post?
别开你自己的玩笑  命是你自己的
Don't kid yourselves. You're on your own in this life,
我们每一个人都是
each and every one of us.
你为何不说说那些战死的机师
KAT: Why don't you tell that to the pilots
为了把你们从星球上营救出来
that died getting you off that rock?
还有盖塔关于莎伦和赛道侦查那颗脉冲星的任务的简报
And Gaeta's briefing Sharon and Racetrack on the scouting mission to the Pulsars.
你的意思是雅典娜与赛道
You mean Athena and Racetrack.
消息传得很快啊
Word travels fast.
是的  确实
Yes, it does.
我理解机师们的士气不高
I understand that morale's taken a hit on the flight deck.
没有什么是我们克服不了的  长官
Nothing we can't handle, sir.
我还被告知泰上校…
I'm also told that Colonel Tigh
花了不少时间在机师娱乐室
is spending a lot of time down in the pilot's rec room.
他和星芭  长官
Both him and Starbuck, sir.
他们组成了一个小圈子 还在对那次救援的事三道四
They've been holding court, second guessing the rescue,
对留在卡拉狄加上的船员没什么口德
badmouthing the crew that stayed up with Galactica.
突然间  正如你这些没参加地面抵抗的人  就不能被信任
Suddenly, if you weren't in the ground war, it's like you can't be trusted.
人们都在听着
And people are listening?
他们的话过头了
Their word carries a lot of weight.
你是对的  他们在打击士气和拉帮结派
You're right, they're destroying morale and unit cohesion.
他们都知道道理的
They both know better.
我不这么认为  长官
I don't think they care, sir.
两个质子在两边分裂 创建力场
HYBRID: Two protons expelled at each coupling site creates them under force.
胚胎已进化到鱼状形态 在A状态前我们不要操作
The embryo becomes a fish that we don't enter until eight plate.
我们在此经历小心翼翼地进化 萎缩
We're here to experience, evolve the little toe, atrophy.
别问我该怎么办 我会在1000光年处死去
Don't ask me how, I'll be dead in 1,000 light years.
谢谢  谢谢  起源转为它的源头
Thank you. Thank you. Genesis turns to its source,
逐步递减 尽管感觉都是一样的
reduction occurs stepwise though the essence is all one.
行终止
End of line.
超光速系统检查  设定诊断功能参数
FTL system check, diagnostic functions within parameters,
重复执行 痛苦是剧烈的
repeats the harlequin, the agony exquisite,
颜色沿着尘埃之路行走
the colors run the path of ashes.
52%的热交换机
Neuronal network run 52% of heat exchanger.
联接多维矩阵
Cross-collateralized with hyperdimensional matrix.
优先于修理指令 继电器转到0  0  0  0
Upper sensors repair ordered, relay to zero, zero, zero, zero...
它能感觉到我们吗?
BALTAR: Is it aware of us?
当然 她能感觉到船上的所有东西
CAPRICA SIX: Of course. She's aware of everything aboard.
行终止
HYBRID: End of line.
新的段落
New paragraph.
胰液在进化矩阵的统一体中流动
Reduction occurs stepwise though the essence is all one.
你知道她在说什么吗?
Do you have any idea what it's talking about?
不
No.
绝大多数赛昂人都认为混合体的意识思维已经疯了
Most Cylons think the conscious mind of the Hybrid has simply gone mad
她所发出的声音对我们来说是无意义的
and the vocalizations we hear are meaningless.
但不是所有人都这么认为
But not everyone thinks that?
你认识的那个李奥本认为
The ones you know as "Leoben"
她口中所说的东西是有含义的
believe that every word out of her mouth means something.
上帝通过她的嘴向我们说话
That God literally speaks to us through her.
她或多或少地控制基地之星  对吧?
She sort of controls the Baseship, does she?
她就是母舰  非常严格地说
Well, she is the Baseship, in a very real sense.
意识疯掉了
A mind gone mad.
她体验生活和我们很不同 盖尤斯
She experiences life very differently than we do, Gaius.
她在天空中游弋
She swims in the heavens,
在星空中欢笑  在宇宙尘埃中呼吸
laughs at stars, breathes in cosmic dust.
也许李奥本是对的
Maybe Leoben's right,
也许她的确能看到上帝
maybe she does see God.
我们在浪费时间
We're wasting time.
跳跃
Jump.
到处都是尸体
There are bodies everywhere.
他们正在死去
Others dying.
这是什么该死的东西?    明显人造的
BALTAR: What the hell is that? Definitely manmade.
你严重脱水 你必须喝点水
You're severely dehydrated. You must drink some water.
杀了我
Kill me.
你不会明白的 这附近没有复活船
You don't understand, there is no Resurrection ship nearby.
你没有机会下载到新的躯体里了 你会就此死去
You will not be downloaded into a new body, you will just be gone.
我看到他们怎么死的了
I saw how they died.
请帮我
Please...
请帮我  我忍受不了了
Please, I can't bear that.
我来这里就是为了帮助你们 好吗?
I'm here to bring help. All right?
我会采一些血样带回基地之星上分析
I'm just gonna take some blood samples for analysis on the Baseship.
到时候我们就有对付病毒的方法了
And then we will be able to make a treatment for the disease.
呼吸  求求你
You must breathe, please.
请你喝点水
Please, take some water.
你是从卡拉狄加上来的
You're... You're from Galactica.
不  我是从基地之星上来的
No. I'm from a Baseship.
告诉我
Tell me,
你知道这是什么吗?
do you know what this is?
我们在附近空间发现它在漂浮
We found it floating at these coordinates.
应该是一种讯标
It must be some kind of
或是记号器
a beacon, a marker.
它看起来很古老了  看起来非常古老
It looks too old. It looks very old.
一定是第13部落遗留下来的  它被感染了 有毒的
It must have been left by the Thirteenth Tribe, infected, poisoned,
是被一些像你一样的人类留下来毁灭我们的
left by some humans like you to destroy us.
什么?
What?
一个带着瘟疫的人类设备
A human device filled with a pestilence.
是你把我们派到这里的
You sent us to this place.
那不是我
It wasn't me.
你知道我们会把它拿上舰
You knew we'd bring it aboard.
你不知道你在说什么了
You don't know what you're saying.
这就是你所说的…
This is the disease...
你知道我们会…
You knew we would...
...病毒    冷静 我是来帮助你们的
...speaking for you. Will you calm down! I am going to bring help.
我是来帮助你们的
I am going to bring help.
你想让其他基地之星也来这里
You wanted the other Baseships to follow.
我不会做任何伤害你的事情
I would never do anything to hurt you.
你想让其他的基地之星过来  你知道它在这儿
You wanted the other Baseships. You knew it was here.
我是过来帮助你们的
I am going to bring help.
安静
Be quiet.
受到同样的感染
Suffer the same infection.
安静  我是过来帮助你们的
Be quiet. I am going to bring help!
你想把我们都消灭
You want to destroy us all!
都是你的错! 你骗了他们
It your fault! You'll lie to them.
闭嘴!     你骗了他们
Shut up! No, you'll lie to them!
闭嘴   你要把他们都带来..
Shut up! You'll bring them here.
都是你的错    闭嘴
It your fault! Shut up!
安静    不 让我…
Be quiet! No, let me...
闭嘴!
Shut up!
不要让我…        闭嘴!
Don't let me... Shut up!
盖尤斯  听到没有?
DORAL: Gaius, do you hear us?
盖尤斯  收到了吗?  还有人活着吗?
Gaius, do you read? Do you read? Are any of them alive?
盖尤斯・波塔尔 你看到什么了
Gaius Baltar, what do you see?
回话 你看到什么了 还有人活着吗
Speak to us. What do you see? Are any of them alive?
我是盖尤斯・波塔尔
This is Gaius Baltar.
我马上回基地之星
I'm returning to the Baseship.
你看到什么了?
DORAL: What do you see?
我什么都没看到
I see nothing.
没有什么有价值的信息
Nothing of consequence.
这儿没什么可做的了
There's nothing left to do here.
没人愿意这样  但我们必须得冒这个可怕的风险
D'ANNA: Nobody likes it, but we have to make a terrible choice.
试着救援他们 会让我们舰队的同伴们带入危险
Do we attempt a rescue and risk the lives of our fleet,
甚至我们的种族  还是让我们离开他们吧
even our species, or do we leave them?
从科学的角度看 无法找到治愈的办法
The answer won't be found in science because there is no cure in science.
不  肯定有方法的
Well, there has to be.
看看他们  他们如此恐惧  我们就这样离他们而去?
Look at them. They're so afraid. Do we just leave them?
然后宣告他们死亡  绝不行
Then their quest ended in death. Absolutely, no.
即便是人类也不会抛弃他们的袍泽
Even the humans don't abandon their own.
他们必须为了大家而牺牲
DORAL: They must be sacrificed for the greater good.
这是个很好的问题
SIMON: There is a greater question.
是的  就是
Yes, there is.
为什么会发生这个事情呢?
How did this happen?
都是因为波塔尔  都是他的错  他故意把我们引到那里
DORAL: Well, it's Baltar. It's his fault, he led us there deliberately.
他一直都在为卡拉狄加工作!
He been working with Galactica the whole time!
那不是我
It wasn't me.
不论你们怎么看我  老实说  我没做!
Whatever you think I did, I didn't do it, honestly!
波塔尔  我们遵照你给的坐标
Baltar, we followed your coordinates,
结果却得了一种没法医治的疾病
and found a disease with no treatment or cure.
很明显这是他们的命运 不会再回来了
If we leave, they're doomed, never to return.
可能上帝会嘲笑我们 因为我们的仁慈
Perhaps God would smile upon us, for our mercy.
哦  听你的    你也就只能说说别人了
Oh, listen to you. You can barely even speak His name.
我们不得不同意   我们没有抛弃我们的兄弟
D'ANNA: We have to agree. We are not leaving our brothers.
够了
D'ANNA: Enough!
我们必须离开
We have to leave.
我们必须跳跃  让他们去面对自己的命运  没有别的办法
We have to jump and leave them to their fate. There is no other way.
梦想的薄雾顺着初起的回响坠落 不再去爱
Mists of dreams drip along the nascent echo and love no more.
行终止
End of Line.
混合体反对
The Hybrid objects.
她没有投票权
She doesn't get a vote.
马上跳跃
Jump the ship.
跳跃
Jump.
这种病毒
D'ANNA: This disease,
一定是从什么地方过来的
it must have come from someplace.
你在被感染的船上发现了什么吗?
So what did you notice on the infected ship?
没有  没有  我和你一样困惑
BALTAR: Nothing. Nothing. I am just as baffled as you are.
你没发现被感染船上有什么可疑的吗?
You noticed nothing suspicious on the infected ship?
没有什么特别的
Nothing whatsoever.
全体起立
CREWMAN: Admiral on deck!
上将
TIGH: Admiral.
给我让一让
Give me the room.
坐在你的位子上
Stay in your seats.
喝点吗?
Have a drink?
把你的佩枪给我
Give me your sidearm.
什么?
What?
你的佩枪
Your sidearm.
嗨  里面还有一发子弹呢
TIGH: Hey! There's a live round in that!
你们和我都不怕它
Now, one of you, and I don't care who,
拾起武器  朝我开枪
pick that weapon up and shoot me.
上将  我不知道…
Admiral, I don't know...
我没说让你讲话
I didn't say to talk.
你也已经说的够多的了
You've done enough of that already.
我说拾起武器 朝我开枪
I said to pick up that weapon and shoot.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
没胆了?
No guts?
你们不是一对吗?
You don't got a pair?
你们两个都是他妈的胆小鬼
You're both frakking cowards.
管好你的嘴         要不呢?
Watch your mouth... Or what?
你让我们剩下的机师互相敌对吗?
You gonna turn the rest of my pilots against each other?
毒害我们的船员?
Poison the crew?
你已经这么做了  少  你们都是
You've already done that, Saul. Both of you.
是啊  如果你希望得到我们的道歉  那是没有的
Yeah, but if you're looking for an apology, it isn't gonna happen.
你过去就像我的女儿一样
You were like a daughter to me once.
不再是了
No more.
你是个散布不满的人  是个毒瘤
You're a malcontent and a cancer,
我不想让你待在我的船上
and I won't have you on my ship.
你现在有个机会
So you have a choice.
要么你明白该怎样做人 怎样做个军官
You can figure out how to become a human being again and an officer,
要么你找个别的地方去生活 离开这艘船
or you can find another place to live off of this ship.
解散
You're dismissed.
你也准备把我从位子上踢下来吗?
Are you gonna kick me out of my chair, too?
听着  我知道你经历了很多
Listen, I know you've been through a lot...
别教育我
Don't patronize me.
说些什么教育我的话
Say what you came here to say.
你满肚子都是怒火 仇恨
You're full of bile. Hatred.
我知道这和艾伦有关 对这件事情我也很抱歉
And I know that it has something to do with Ellen, and I'm sorry for that.
如果你需要时间  少  你可以随便花多长时间
And if you need time, Saul, well, you take all the time you want.
但我要管理整艘船
But I got to run a ship.
我不能忍受一个独眼的醉鬼在这儿坐着
The last thing I need is a one-eyed drunk sitting down here,
还散播不满和反抗情绪
sowing discontent and disobedience.
所以我再跟你说一次  少
So I'll tell you once again, Saul.
你可以把武器拾起来  朝我开枪
You can pick up that weapon and kill me,
或是把你的屁股挪回你的地方并且不要再离开
or you can get your ass back into your quarters and not leave
直到你表现得像我在过去30年里认识的那个男人
until you're ready to act like the man that I've known for the past 30 years.
那个人不会再存在了  比尔
That man doesn't exist anymore, Bill.
你也不会再见到我了
And you won't be seeing me again.
对 那是我和他共事的原因
MAN 1: Yeah, that's why I work with him.
那就是我要说的
MAN 2: Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
再拿条毛巾给我
MAN 3: Grab another towel for me.
我们要过去了
Yeah, we got to get up there.
好
MAN 4: All right.
噢  我的天  它就在这里
Oh, my Gods, it's right there.
狮头星云  还有闪耀的眼睛
The Lion's Head nebula and the Blinking Eye.
我们的赌注  那是通往地球的道路
Holy crap, it's the road to Earth.
噢  我的天  让我们离开这鬼地方
Oh, my Gods! Let's get the frak out of here.
我来准备跳跃
I'll start the jump.
当神愤怒起来 巨人也会倒下
When Gods' anger awakens, even the mighty shall fall.
靠!  雅典娜  我们得离开这里
Frak! Athena, we need to get out of here!